# Aayam K. Shrestha

Linkedin.com/in/aayamshrestha

Email : shrestaa@oregonstate.edu Github.com/idigitopia | (+1) 541-368-8894

#### STATEMENT

Hoping to play my part on not just solving intelligence, but more importantly ensuring that its intent aligns with ours. Believer of a digitopia and a spiritual seeker. *Current Research:* Deep Grounding of AI planners, Bridging the gap between symbolic planners and data-driven learners.

Research Interests: Deep Reinforcement Learning, Knowledge Graphs.

### **EDUCATION**

**Oregon State University** 

Corvallis, OR

PhD. in Computer Science; GPA: 3.85/4.0

Sept. 2018 - Sept 2023 [Expected]

Kathmandu Engineering College, Tribhuvan University

Kathmandu, Nepal Aug. 2012 – Apr. 2016

Bachelors in Computer Engineering; GPA: 4.0/4.0 (Valedictorian)

## EXPERIENCE

Oregon State University

Corvallis, OR

 ${\it Graduate \; Research \; Assistant -- Advisor : Prof. \; Alan \; Fern}$ 

Sept. 2018 - Present

○ Research: Deep Reinforcement Learning and Symbolic Reasoning/Planning.
○ Project: Part of the OSUs team for DARPA Machine Common Sense Project ☑.

IDEA Lab - Team member — Advisor : Prof. Arash Termehchy

June 2018 - Feb. 2019

• Research: Working in the intersection of knowledge graphs and Machine Learning.

#### Logic Information Systems.

Blommington, MN May 2016 - Aug. 2018

Business Intelligence Engineer

o Project: Develop and maintain large-scale enterprise Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence solutions

- o BI Consulting: Off-shore consulting for clients Alex & Ani, Holland and Barett, Gander Mountain, and Makro.
- Research: Customer Experience Analytics over in-house data lake. *Data Sources:* customer call audio, text reviews and curated twitter feeds.

#### Skills and Tools

- Languages: Python, C#, R.
- Frameworks and Libraries: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Pandas, Wandb, SKlearn, Hadoop, Spark, ASP.NET, GraphQL
- Databases: MySQL, MsSQL, OraclePL/SQL, Netezza, Teradata, Cypher-Neo4J
- Default Stack: Numpy, Pytorch, SKlearn, Pandas, Wandb

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. **Aayam Shrestha**, Stefan Lee, Prasad Tadepalli and Alan Fern. "DeepAveragers: Offline Reinforcement Learning by Solving Derived Non-Parametric MDPs". Under Review, *ICLR 2021*. (pdf)
- 2. Aayam Shrestha, Stefan Lee, Prasad Tadepalli and Alan Fern. "DeepAveragers: Offline Reinforcement Learning by Solving Derived Non-Parametric MDPs". Offline Reinforcement Learning Workshop, NeurIPS 2020 (Oral). (pdf)
- 3. Yodsawalai Chodpathumwan, **Aayam Shrestha**, Stephen Ramsey, Arash Termehchy. "Structurally Robust Similarity Search". Under Review, SIGMOD 2021. (pdf)

## Projects

- DAC-MDPs: Deriving non parametric MDPs for Offline Reinforcement learning and zero-shot transfer learning. (2020)
- BigMDP: Library for creating and solving large MDPs with million of states. GPU optimized VI solver. (2019)
- Semi Supervised Mars Imageset Classification &: Using k-means clustering over discrete learned features. (2019)
- Obj2Obj GAN  $\sigma$ : Masked Image to Image translation using GANs for object inpainting. (2018)
- Bias in Knowledge Graphs &: Identifying bias of ML algorithms for different information preserving variations (2018)
- Vehicle Traffic Prediction: For optimizing traffic flow using RNNs on real world dataset. (2017)
- Gurukul: Integrating analytics and data-driven recommendations for College ERP (2015)